Guide to the Davenport College, Yale University, Records of the Master
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Davenport College, Yale University, records of the master
1930-1979
RU 444
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
23
The records consist of student records for the Classes of 1932-1951 and correspondence and committee files of Master Emerson Tuttle.
Davenport College (Yale University)
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 13-F-2 (YRG 13-F-2), Records of the master of Davenport College.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of student records for the Classes of 1932-1951 and correspondence and committee files of Master Emerson Tuttle.
Biographical / Historical
The title "Master" for chief executive officers of residential colleges was changed to "Head of College" in April of 2016.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the materials is partially restricted. See inventory for details.
College students; Student housing; Universities and colleges -- Administration; Tuttle, H. E. (Henry Emerson), 1890-1946; Davenport College (Yale University); Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Student housing; Yale University -- Students
- Records, 1932-1951; Accession 19ND-A-397
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2026
  - An Informal History of Davenport, 1933-1935 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - Council of Masters secretary's files
    - 1934-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1938-1939 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1940-1941 (Box 1, Folder 6-7)
    - 1941-1942 (Box 1, Folder 8-9)
    - 1942-1943 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - 1943-1944 (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
    - 1944-1946 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - 1947-1948 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - 1948-1949 (Box 1, Folder 16-17)
    - 1948-1951 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - 1949-1950 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - 1950-1951 (Box 1, Folder 20-21)
  - Letters and excerpts from bound copy, 1935-1937 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, 1936-1939 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Reports of official committees, 1940-1941 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Personnel
    - 1935-1939 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - 1938-1939 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - 1948-1949 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - House committee, 1942-1943 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Requests to be acted upon, 1949-1951 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Associate fellows of the colleges, 1948-1951 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Housekeeping reports, 1950-1951 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence, 1950-1951 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Miscellaneous reports, 1931-1935 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence, 1941-1943 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Gifts to college, 1935-1944 (Box 1, Folder 35-36)
  - Lists, 1943-1945 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    Scope and Contents
    Contains lists of student names and room numbers, students withdrawn from Yale, and similar information.
  - Students, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Dining hall, 1933-1935 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Bursary and chief aid, 1935-1936 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Functions, 1934-1935 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Notices, 1934-1935 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Guest suite, 1935-1938 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Fellows, 1934-1935 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Thanksgiving dinner, 1934 November 27, 1934-1935 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Commencement, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Functions, 1936-1937 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Student gifts, 1933-1934 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Educational budget, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Educational policy, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Fellows: correspondence and lists, 1933-1934 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Capehart (record player), 1936-1937 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Davenport and college athletics, 1932-1937 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Fellows - lists, 1934-1935 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Associate fellows, 1936-1937 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Military-university relations, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - College and Sheffield rules revisions, 1934-1935 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Davenport College entertainment, 1946-1948 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Allocations: H.E. Tuttle - Committee on Distribution, 1935-1938 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - B, 1934-1944 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Bayne-Jones, Stanhope, 1942- (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Broadcasting WODC, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - C, 1936-1943 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Carnegie Corporation, 1932-1941 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - College plan - athletics, 1931-1932 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Committee on History of Art, 1936-1940 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Garstin, D. V., 1939-1940 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Dining hall investigation, 1936-1937 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Angell, James R., 1935-1945 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Allocations (fall 1942), 1940-1943 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Art Gallery (acting director), 1942-1944 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Dunn, F. S., "Anglo-American Relationships", 1943 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Colleges - miscellaneous, 1932-1934 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Farnam, Thomas W., 1935-1943 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - F, 1936-1945 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Football, 1941-1942 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - French, Robert S., 1936-1944 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Furniss, Edgar S. (Provost), 1936-1943 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - H, 1935-1943 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Harvard Conference, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Room applications, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Rooms, 1944-1945 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Boswell Papers, 1934-1935 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Dining Halls - Miss Bowers, 1940-1942 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Aurelian Honor Society, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Committee on Institute for Veterans, 1944-1945 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Curator of Prints
    - Greene Collection, 1937-1939 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - 1934-1939 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - 1943-1944 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - 1932-1933 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Harvard, 1926-1933 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Associate fellows, 1935-1936-06 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Yale Athletic Association, 1932-1941 (Box 2, Folder 35-36)
  - University: W, X, Y, Z, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - University: T, U, V, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - University: S (including Charles Seymour), 1934 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - University: O, P, Q, R (including James Gamble Rogers), 1934 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Pomfret School list, 1933-1934 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - University: M,N, 1933-1936 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - University: K, L (including Kingsley Trust), 1933-1935 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - University: H, I, J (including Frederic B. Johnson), 1934-1941 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Silliman portrait, 1938-1940 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Class Dinner, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - University: E, F (including Thomas W. Farnam, Sidney H. Francis, Robert D. French), 1934 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - University: D, E, 1934-1935 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Davenport report, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - H. Emerson Tuttle correspondence, 1930-1945 (Box 2, Folder 50)
- Correspondence, 1930-1945; Accession 1945-A-002
  The materials are open for research.
  - Acheson, Dean G., 1942-1943 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Allocations, Committee on, 1935-1936 (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
  - Angell, James R, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Athletic Association and Budgets, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Auchincloss, Hugh, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Aurelian Honor Society, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Bissell Bowl, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Budget, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - C-D-E, 1932-1933 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Day, George Parmly, 1932-1933 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - DeVane, William C., 1942-1944 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - F, 1932-1933 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Farnham, Thomas W., 1931-1933 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Fellows, 1934-1938 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Fellows: furniture, 1932-1934 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Fraternities: Committee to Study Relation of Fraternities and Colleges. Academic, 1932-1933 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - G, 1932-1934 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Garstin, D.V., 1933 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Graduate Club Association, 1933-1934 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - H-I-J-K, 1932-1937 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Johnson, Frederick B, 1932-1933 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Knollenberg, Bernhard, 1938-1941 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - L-M, 1932-1933 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Lohrnann, Carl A., 1932-1944 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Lovett, Sidney, 1932-1933 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - MacLeish, Archibald, 1934-1936 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Mendell, Clarence, 1933-1943 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Merritt, Alfred K., 1933 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - N-O, 1933-1942 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Nettleton, George H., 1937-1938 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - P-R, 1931-1944 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Personnel Director, Nyman, R.C., 1940-1944 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Rogers, James Gamble, 1931-1938 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - S, 1931-1933 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Scholarships, Committee on, 1940-1941 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Seymour, Charles, 1930-1944 (Box 3, Folder 37 - 38)
  - Sizer, Theodore, 1942-1945 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Smith, Elliott Dunlap, 1933 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - T-U-V, 1933 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Tighe, Laurence G., 1942-1943 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Undergraduate Activities, Committee on, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - W-X-Y, 1933 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - War Training Co-ordinating Committees minutes, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Wilder, Thorton H., 1934-1936 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Yale News: clippings re: meal plans, 1933-1934 (Box 3, Folder 47)
- Subject and fellowship files, diaries and printed material, circa 1960-1979; Accession 2001-A-151
  - Fellows files and miscellaneous subject files (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous subject files and Davenport College diaries (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous subject files, 1960's - 1970's (Box 3–4)
  - Subject files and newsletter (Box 5)
  - Subject files (Box 6–10)
  - Fellows files (Box 11–12)
  - Fellows files, diaries, student publications, history of Davenport College (Box 13)
  - Subject files (Box 14)
  - Miscellaneous subject files and subject files (Box 15)